swoogo.com 2019-10-11

# Privacy — Swoogo | Event Marketing Software

Swoogo is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to our Websites (www.swoogo.com and get.swoogo.com) and our Event Management Software, including our associated mobile applications (Mobile Apps) owned and controlled by Swoogo. This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. If you do not agree with the data practices described in this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Websites or the Event Management Software. 

We periodically update this Privacy Policy. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by sending you an email notification.

While we will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our treatment of the information you provide us, please write to us by email at privacy@swoogo.com.

###  **1\. USE OF THE EVENT MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE BY SWOOGO AND OUR CUSTOMERS**

 **The Swoogo Event Management Software**

Our online Event Management Software allows any company that uses it (our customers and Swoogo itself) to create and share event registration content. The information added to the Event Management Software, either by site visitors providing their contact information or when an Event Management Software user adds the information, is stored and managed on our service providers' servers. This information is then used to contact visitors about their interest in the company's event and interact with the company. Swoogo provides the Event Management Software to our customers for their own marketing, lead generation, and customer service needs, and we use it to meet Swoogo’s related needs. 

 **Use by Swoogo**

We use our own Event Management Software to build webpages that people can visit to learn more about Swoogo. Information that we collect and manage using the Event Management Software for our own marketing belongs to us and is used, disclosed and protected according to this Privacy Policy. 

 **Use by Our Customers**

Our customers use the Event Management Software to build webpages that people can visit to learn more about their business and events that they are running. Swoogo does not control the content of these webpages or the types of information that our customers may choose to collect or manage using the Event Management Software. That information belongs to them and is used, disclosed and protected by them according to their privacy policies and is not subject to this Privacy Policy. Swoogo processes our customers' information as they direct and in accordance with our agreements with our customers, and we store it on our service providers' servers, but we do not have control over its collection or management. Our agreements with our customers prohibit us from using that information, except as necessary to provide and improve the Event Management Software, as permitted by this Privacy Policy, and as required by law. We have no direct relationship with individuals who provide Personal Information to our customers. Swoogo acknowledges that you have the right to access your Personal Information. Our customers control and are responsible for correcting, deleting or updating information they have collected from you using the Event Management Software. If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. We may work with our customers to help them provide notice to their visitors about their data collection, processing and usage. Our agreements with our customers prohibit them from using the Event Management Software to collect, manage, or process Sensitive Information. We are not responsible for our customers' use of information they collect on the Event Management Software.

Swoogo collects information under the direction of its customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information it processes. If you are a customer of one of our customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our customer that use our Event Management Software, please contact the customer that you interact with directly. We may transfer Personal Information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our customers.

 **"Sensitive Information"**

This refers to credit or debit card numbers, personal financial account information, Social Security numbers, passport numbers, driver's license numbers or similar personal identifiers, racial or ethnic origin, physical or mental health condition or information, or other employment, financial or health information. The only exception to this is credit or debit card details that are processed in designated Swoogo system credit card fields, data in these fields is housed securely in line with our externally audited PCI Level 1 standards of compliance and not visible to our customers for event fee processing reasons.

###  **2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

 **When You Visit our Websites**

You are free to explore the Websites without providing any Personal Information about yourself. When you visit the Websites or register for more information, we request that you provide Personal Information about yourself, and we collect Navigational Information. 

 **"Personal Information"**

This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the Websites, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as is publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.

Personal Information also includes Navigational Information or Payment Information where such information can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Navigational information refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. Please see the "Navigation Information" section below. We collect and process payment information from you when you subscribe to the Event Management Software, including credit cards numbers and billing information, using third party PCI-compliant service providers. Except for this, we do not collect Sensitive Information from you.

 **Log Files**

When you use our services our view content provided by us, we automatically collect information about your computer hardware and software. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Swoogo for the operation of the Event Management Software, to maintain quality of the Event Management Software, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Swoogo Website. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

 **Information we collect from third parties**

From time to time, we may receive Personal Information about you from third party sources including partners with which we offer co-branded services or engage in joint marketing activities, and publicly available sources such as social media websites.

 **Information About Children**

The Websites are not intended for or targeted at children under 16, and we do not knowingly or intentionally collect information about children under 16 If you believe that we have collected information about a child under 16, please contact us at privacy@swoogo.com, so that we may delete the information.

###  **3\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

 **Compliance with Our Privacy Policy**

We use the information we collect only in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Customers who subscribe to our Event Management Software are obligated through our agreements with them to comply with this Privacy Policy.

We Never Sell Personal Information

We will never sell your Personal Information to any third party. 

Use of Personal Information

In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may use your Personal Information to:

improve your browsing experience by personalizing the Websites and to improve the Event Management Software;  
send information or Swoogo content to you which we think may be of interest to you by post, email, or other means and send you marketing communications relating to our business;  
promote use of our services to you and share promotional and information content with you in accordance with your communication preferences;  
provide other companies with statistical information about our users -- but this information will not be used to identify any individual user;  
send information to you regarding changes to our Customer Terms of Service, Privacy Policy (including the Cookie Policy), or other legal agreements  
meet legal requirements.

We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, we do not transfer your Personal Information to the third party.

We use the information collected through our Event Management Software by our customers for the following purposes:

to provide the Event Management Software (which may include the detection, prevention and resolution of security and technical issues);  
to respond to customer support requests; and  
otherwise to fulfill the obligations under the Swoogo Customer Terms of Service. 

Legal basis for processing Personal Information (EEA visitors only)

If you are a visitor/customer located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), Swoogo Solutions Limited is the data controller of your personal information. Swoogo's Data Protection Officer can be contacted at privacy@swoogo.com. 

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

 **Use of Navigational Information**

We use Navigational Information to operate and improve the Websites and the Event Management Software. We may also use Navigational Information alone or in combination with Personal Information to provide you with personalized information about Swoogo. 

 **Customer Testimonials and Comments**

We post customer testimonials and comments on our Websites, which may contain Personal Information. We obtain each customer's consent via email prior to posting the customer's name and testimonial.

 **Use of Credit Card Information**

If you give us credit card information, we use it solely to collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf.

 **Security of your Personal Information**

We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. All Personal Information is protected using appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures.

 **Social Media Features**

Our Websites include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features.  Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the companies providing them.

 **External Websites**

Our Websites provide links to other websites. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the content or practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to any privacy and other policies they may have.

 **Public Forums**

We offer publicly accessible message boards, blogs, and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose any information through our public message boards, blogs, or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. We will correct or delete any information you have posted on the Websites if you so request, as described in "Opting Out and Unsubscribing" below.

 **Retention of Personal Information**

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information. as described in further detail below.  After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible. 

We retain Personal Information that you provide to us where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, as long as is required in order to contact you about the Event Management Software or our other services, or as needed to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Information, on request, we can securely delete the information or anonymise it or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your Personal Information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. We will delete this information from the servers at an earlier date if you so request, as described in "To Unsubscribe from Our Communications" below.

If you provide information to our customers as part of their use of the Event Management Software, our customers decide how long to retain the personal information they collect from you. If a customer terminates its use of the Event Management Software, then we will provide customer with access to all information stored for the customer by the Event Management Software, including any Personal Information provided by you, for export by the customer according to our agreement with our customer. After termination, we may, on request, unless legally prohibited, delete all customer information, including your Personal Information, from the Event Management Software.

If you have elected to receive marketing communications from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our content, products, or services, such as when you last opened an email from us or ceased using your Swoogo account.  We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created. 

###  **4\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

 **Service Providers**

We employ other companies and people to provide services to visitors to our Websites, our customers, and users of the Event Management Software and may need to share your information with them to provide information, products or services to you. Examples may include removing repetitive information from prospect lists, analyzing data or performing statistical analysis, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, supplementing the information you provide us in order to provide you with better service, and providing customer service or support. In all cases where we share your information with such agents, we explicitly require the agent to acknowledge and adhere to our privacy and customer data handling policies.

 **Swoogo Partners**

In addition, we may share data with trusted partners to contact you based on your request to receive such communications, help us perform statistical analysis, or provide customer support. Such third parties are prohibited from using your Personal Information except for these purposes, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

We partner with trusted third parties to provide you with co-marketing content that we think may be relevant to you. When you engage with these co-marketing partners, we will tell you who we are sharing data with, and provide a link to the co-marketing partner’s privacy policy so you can learn more about how to opt-out of the partner’s communications. These co-marketing partners are required to adhere to our privacy and data protection policies. For more information on our co-marketing program, see this page.

 **Corporate Events**

If we (or our assets) are acquired by another company, whether by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or otherwise, that company would receive all information gathered by Swoogo on the Websites and the Event Management Software. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your Personal Information, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

 **Compelled Disclosure**

We reserve the right to use or disclose your Personal Information if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a law, court order, or legal process.

###  **5\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF INFORMATION**

Some of the third parties described in this privacy policy, which provide services to us under contract, are based in other countries that may not have equivalent privacy and data protection laws to the country in which you reside. When we share information of customers in the European Economic Area or Switzerland, we make use of the EU-U.S. and European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses, binding corporate rules for transfers to data processors, or other appropriate legal mechanisms to safeguard the transfer.  

###  **6\. COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES**

Cookies

Swoogo and its partners use cookies or similar technologies (such as web beacons) to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

 **Third Party Tracking Technologies**

The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our Privacy Policy or Cookie Policy. 

###  **7\. HOW TO ACCESS & CONTROL YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Reviewing, Correcting and Removing Your Personal Information

You have the following data protection rights:

You can request access, correction, updates or deletion of your personal information.  
You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information.  
If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.  
You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at privacy@swoogo.com. We will respond to your request to change, correct, or delete your information within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

 **Anti-Spam Policy**

We prohibit use of the Event Management Software to send unsolicited commercial email in violation of applicable laws, and require the inclusion in every invitation email sent using the Event Management Software of an "opt-out" mechanism and other required information. We require all of our customers to agree to adhere to the Acceptable Use Policy at all times, and any violations of the Acceptable Use Policy by a customer can result in immediate suspension or termination of the Event Management Software.

 **To Unsubscribe From Our Communications**

You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of our emails, updating your communication preferences, or by sending us email us at privacy@swoogo.com. Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with us or the Event Management Software. 

 **To Unsubscribe from Our Customers' Communications**

Our customers are solely responsible for their own marketing emails and other communications; we cannot unsubscribe you from their communications. You can unsubscribe from our customers' marketing communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of their emails, or by contacting them directly.
